A Heartland Christmas is a family, tv movie film directed by Dean Bennett.
Christmas comes to Heartland, along with an anonymous call about starving horses stranded by
an avalanche in the Rocky Mountains, which send Amy and Ty to their rescue.
Amy Fleming, played by Amber Marshall.
Joanna Hawke, played by Helene Joy.
Will Vernon, played by Nicholas Campbell.
Ashley Stanton, played by Cindy Busby.
Tim Fleming, played by Chris Potter.
Lou Fleming, played by Michelle Morgan.
Heartland is a Canadian family drama television series
which debuted on CBC on October 14, 2007.
Heartland follows sisters Amy and Lou Fleming, their grandfather Jack Bartlett, and Ty Borden through
the highs and lows of life at their horse ranch in the fictional town of Hudson, Alberta.
The plot focuses on Amy, who inherited her mother's ability to heal abused and damaged horses after
a tragic accident that led to significant changes in the lives of the characters.
Heartland airs in Canada on CBC at 7 pm (7:30 pm in Newfoundland) on Sundays.
The series also airs in the United States on the UpTV and formerly
on the defunct Light TV digital broadcast network.
It is also distributed online on Netflix internationally (excluding Canada).
The series previously also aired on The CW before
being transferred solely to UP by 2010.
The show became the longest-running one-hour scripted drama in Canadian television history on
October 19, 2014, when it surpassed the previous 124-episode record set by Street Legal.
As of December 7, 2025, 279 episodes of Heartland have
aired, concluding the nineteenth season.
The fourteenth season premiered in Canada on January 10, 2021, and airing later in the United States on UP's UP Faith and Family streaming
service on May 6, 2021 and premiered on linear Up TV starting July 8, 2021 as part of the summer Thursday night programming schedule.
The fifteenth season premiered on Up Faith & Family starting in
March 17, 2022 and premiered later on Up TV on May 19.
The show was renewed for a 15-episode 16th season on June 1,
2022 and started production on the same day.
It premiered in the fall in Canada and will premiere on June 1, 2023 on Up Faith
and Family and in the summer on the main Up TV channel in the US.
Up Faith and Family season 16, episode 10 was a 'mid-season finale'.
Episode 11 was held until fall, September 21, 2023.
In May 2025, the series was renewed for a nineteenth season confirmed for another 10 episodes which was confirmed and announced on the same day by lead
actress Amber Marshall, in a video posted to social and on her official YouTube channel letting fans know that production was underway.
Filming later began in June and at CBC Television's 2025 upfront for the fall 2025-26 season television
season, it was announced that the season would premiere sometime in October in Canada.
It was later revealed that it would premiere on October 2, with its US premiere to follow on November 4 exclusively on UP Faith & Family and it premiered with a live interactive virtual event for fans featuring interviews
from the cast and crew of the show and a live watch party for fans of the show to interact with other fans of the show in an interactive messaging chat box on screen with real time comments being shown live.
New episodes will air weekly with one episode per week until December 5 where the show will take a break
and then return in January 2026 with the remaining new episodes until early February.
This is the first time new episodes of the series were released in tandem between Canada and the US unlike previous, whereas the show would premiere a new season in the fall in Canada and
then premiere sometime later on in the winter, spring or summer in the US the following year under a deal between both broadcasters Up TV and CBC and producer SEVEN24 Films.
This follows a similar production release schedule pattern to that of the show Murdoch Mysteries, which airs on Ovation TV and streams on Acorn TV, a streaming platform owned by AMC Networks, in the US, where previously new seasons were released in Canada in the fall on CBC, then air in either January or February of the next on Ovation on linear TV, then stream on Acorn TV in March
or April every year in the US, however now has reverted to releasing new episodes in the US and Canada on TV, while Ovation airs a repeat on Saturdays as part of its "Mystery Alley" block, and still so far releases on streaming on Acorn TV in the springtime of every year, starting from Season 18 in October 2024, after the Season 17 finale completed airing in May.